Guide to the John Zuccotti Papers 1956-2015 MS 3018
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. General Subjects, 1966-2013; 4.71 Linear feet
  - Labor/Management Relations (Folder 4 of 6), 1989-1989 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    Includes various arbitrated matters between transit authorities and the Transport Workers Union Local 100. Also includes the handbook of "Policy Instruction: Drugs and Controlled Substances" for the transit authorities.
  - Labor/Management Relations (Folder 5 of 6), 1985 April 1 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
    Includes the "Agreement between New York City Transit Authority, Manhattan and Bronx Surface Transit Operating Authority, and Transport Workers Union of America, AFL-CIO, Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100, AFL-CIO."
  - Labor/Management Relations (Folder 6 of 6), 1988 April 1 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
  - "Monthly Report on Key New York City Economic Indicators", 1986 November (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
    Includes the report with narrative and statistics prepared by Program Planners, Inc., with a memo summarizing the report for Zuccotti.
  - "Real Estate Investment Proposal: Crescent Beach at Arverne", 1986 January (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
    Includes the informational brochure provided to potential investors by Starrett Housing Corporation.
  - "Agreement of Lease among New York State Urban Development Corporation and Roosevelt Island Associates and Roosevelt Island Operating Corporation" for Northtown Phase II, 1986 August 4 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
  - Memorandum to John Zuccotti re: Bond Hotel, 1986 July 31 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14)
    Concerns a legal analysis of whether, in a particular circumstance, an occupied single room occupancy (SRO) dwelling could be demolished.
  - Citizens Commission on AIDS, 1987-1994 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
    Zuccotti co-chaired the Commission. Includes the agenda for the Commission's first meeting (22 September 1987); draft workplace principles (1988); the final report AIDS: Is There a Will to Meet the Challenge? (February 1991); a later publication, Orphans of the HIV Epidemic: Unmet Needs in Six U.S. Cities, co-authored by the Commission's former Executive Director, Carol Levine; and some reference material.
  - Toward a Comprehensive Policy on Homelessness, 1987 February 24 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 16)
    This is the report to Mayor Edward I. Koch of his Advisory Task Force on the Homeless, of which Zuccotti was a member.
  - Merger with Brown & Wood, 1986-1987? (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes letters of congratulations and clippings concerning Tufo & Zuccotti's merger with Brown, Wood, Ivey, Mitchell & Petty to form the firm Brown & Wood. Also includes a publicity brochure for Brown & Wood from the late 1980s, with Zuccotti pictured.
  - New York Ascendant: The Report of the Commission on the Year 2000, 1987 June (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Midtown Development Review, 1987 July (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    Report issued by the Department of City Planning.
  - Regional Mobility Conference (3 folders), 1979, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4-6)
    Zuccotti led the workshop "Implementing Mobility Improvements" at this conference organized by the Bi-State Transportation Forum (13 December 1988). Includes program, outline for Zuccotti's workshop, pre-conference papers and other preparatory material (1988) and the post-conference Summary and a follow-on report "Regional Transportation: Current Conditions and Future Prospects: An Interagency Assessment" (1989). The file also holds the report Regional Recovery: The Business of the Eighties (1979), issued by the Port Authority of New York & New Jersey's Committee on the Future.
  - The Role of Amenities in the Land Use Process, 1988 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    Includes the report by a special committee of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York and the related press release.
  - New York City: The Challenge Ahead. 50th Anniversary of the City Planning Commission, Conference Proceedings, 1988 November 29 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
  - Olympia & York (4 folders), 1987-1996 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9-12)
    Includes documents from 1988-1989 when O & Y was a client of Zuccotti's while he was at Brown & Wood, and from 1990 forward when he led O & Y. The documents principally concern tax assessment decreases on O & Y's properties and the resulting press coverage of the matter (1988) and O & Y's financial difficulties in the early 1990s. Most of the latter are press clippings. Other documents include a briefing note for Zuccotti prior to his meeting with Mayor David Dinkins in July 1991; a photograph of Dinkins, Zuccotti and others, signed by Dinkins, at an O & Y project unveiling (January 1990); a photograph of Zuccotti with Paul Reichmann; a draft of a resignation letter from O & Y for Zuccotti, not used (1992); a copy of Reichmann's formal resignation from O & Y (1993); and marketing material for outsourced administrative services from Automated Property Administration (1996).
  - Managerial Review Commission, 1991 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
    Includes two versions of the Commission's report to Mayor Dinkins (July/September 1991 and December 1991); an "Interim Report on New York City's Economy, Office Space Market and Fiscal Conditions" (8 March 1991), prepared by Program Planners, Inc.; and various documents found within the Program Planners publication, including an agenda for the Commission's 10 April 1991 meeting, notes on New York's continuing fiscal problem, property tax analysis by the Real Estate Board of New York, and other documents.
  - New York City Commission on the Homeless (2 folders), 1992 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15-16)
    Zuccotti was a member of the Commission, chaired by Andrew M. Cuomo. Includes two documents: transcript of the Commission's public hearing held on 14 January 1992 and the final report The Way Home: A New Direction in Social Policy (February 1992).
  - Shaping the City's Future, 1993 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
    New York City's planning and zoning report, issued by the Planning Commission, for public discussion.
  - Lower Manhattan Plans, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 18)
    Includes copies of the booklet Plan for Lower Manhattan issued by the Department of City Planning (1993) and a presentation "A Plan for the Revitalization of Lower Manhattan" prepared by the Lower Manhattan Task Force (15 December 1994).
  - Alliance for Downtown New York (2 folders), 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 19-20)
    Includes two reports to the Alliance: one prepared by Hamilton, Rabinovitz & Alschuler concerning the residential market, and one prepared by Penn + Schoen Associates on a survey of public opinion.
  - Real Property Tax Fact Book, 1996 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 21)
    First edition of publication by The Real Estate Board of New York.
  - "Abraham D. Beame: A New York Story", 2001 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 22)
    2001 La Guardia and Wagner Archives Calendar. Includes biographical notes and images from Beame's life. Zuccotti appears in one image, at June.
  - Weil, Gotshal & Manges Newsletters, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    Includes two newsletters: "Bankruptcy Bulletin," Vol. 3, No. 12 (December 1996) and "Business & Securities Litigator," Vol. 8, No. 1 (January 1997), which focuses on fiduciary duties of directors of financially troubled corporations.
  - "Blue Ribbon Committee on Improving the Effectiveness of Corporate Audit Committees. Opening Remarks of Ira M. Millstein", 1999 February 8 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
  - New York City Charter Revision Commission, 1999, 2001 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    Includes the preliminary recommendations for charter revision from the staff to the Commission for both 27 July 1999 and 27 July 2001.
  - Columbia University, 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    Includes background material for the Executive Committee meeting of 7 April 2003, including a schematic of Manhattanville showing Columbia's then-current and anticipated ownership, and architectural plans by Polshek Partnershipo showing the relation of Columbia's southeast site to the Cathedral of St. John the Divine.
  - Lower Manhattan Transportation, 2003 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    Includes Lower Manhattan Transportation Strategies, co-published by the Lower Manhattan Development Corporation, Port Authority, and others. Also includes the Real Estate Board of New York's paper "Zoning and Manufacturing: A Balanced Approach to New York City's Growth"; a flier protesting a proposed West Street Tunnel; a letter from Community Board No. 1 concerning a proposed bridge along Vesey Street; a fact sheet concerning a feasibility study for the extension of Route 9A bypass tunnel to Albany Street; documents concerning using Liberty Bonds for downtown projects.
  - Lower Manhattan Development Corporation: Progress Report, 2001-2004, 2005? (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
  - Balanced Housing for a Smart Region: Policies for Addressing the Housing Problems of the New York Metropolitan Region, 2006 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
    Includes the report published by Citizens Housing & Planning Council and the Regional Plan Association, the related press release, and notes on high impact strategies for housing for working families from American Property Financing/Wachovia Bank.
  - Growth or Gridlock? The Economic Case for Traffic Relief and Transit Improvement for a Greater New York, 2006 December (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8)
    Report published by the Partnership for New York City.
  - "Plan NYC." Brochure from the Mayor's [Michael R. Bloomberg] Sustainability Advisory Board, 2006? (Offsite-box 14, Folder 9)
  - "Economic Development Policy Advisory Committee Report to Governor-elect Spitzer and Lt. Governor-elect Paterson", 2006 December 15 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10)
    Co-chaired by Dan Carp, Ken Chenault, and Felix Rohatyn; Zuccotti was a member.
  - Manhattan West Side Development, 2007 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 11)
    Includes a Brookfield Properties presentation "Eastern and Western Rail Yards" (2007 March 8) and an unattributed and undated presentation "Recent/Current Development: Gansevoort Market and Far West Chelsea." (These were found inside the PlanNYC brochure above.)
  - World Trade Center Memorial Foundation, 2007 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
    Primarily includes documents concerning a fundraising breakfast for the Foundation at Gracie Mansion attended by representatives of the construction/real estate sector. Also includes Zuccotti's talking points for the Foundation's Board meeting of 25 January 2007.
  - Economic Challenges, 2009 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 13)
    Includes Reviving the City of Aspiration: A Study of the Challenges Facing New York City's Middle Class, published by the Center for an Urban Future, and the results of a survey of attendees at a Pension Real Estate Association (PREA) conference.
  - Doris Duke Charitable Foundation, 2010-2011 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 14)
    Includes Deborah Pope's presentation to the Foundation board on 14 September 2010 about Shangri-La (Hawaii) and the catalogue Extraordinary Vision: Doris Duke and the Newport [Rhode Island] Restoration Foundation.
  - PATH Extension to Newark Liberty Airport, 1975, 2011 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    Includes documents, including kick-off meeting presentation and preliminary findings, related to the Alliance for Downtown New York's engagement of the Regional Plan Association to perform a study for a one-seat ride from the World Trade Center to Newark Airport in New Jersey (2011). The folder also holds the 1975 report of the Mayor's {Beame) Policy Committee, Transportation: Policy and Programs.
  - How New York City Won the Olympics, 2011 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    Includes the report published by NYU's Rudin Center for Transportation Policy and Management, with a transmittal letter to Zuccotti, and publicity items for the report.
  - Jim Gill's Book Party, 2009, 2011 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    Hosted by Zuccotti on 9 November 2011. Also includes Gill's remarks on receiving Fordham's Lifetime Achievement Award (2009).
  - Program for the Dedication of "The Kneeling Fireman" Memorial in Front of the Midtown Emigrant Bank Building, 2011 September 22 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Zuccotti Park. Re-Opening, 2006 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    Includes press coverage of the re-opening of One Liberty Plaza and its renaming as Zuccotti Park.
  - Zuccotti Park. Occupy Wall Street (2 folders), 2011 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6-7)
    Includes Brookfield emails, press coverage, complaints, and other documents related to the protests/occupation on the plaza.
    Related Materials at N-YHS
    N-YHS holds a collection of documents related to Occupy Wall Street in New York City.
  - The Trust for Governors Island (2 folders), 2013 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8-9)
    Includes various publicity material and proposals concerning the island in relation to interesting Zuccotti as a member of the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation.
  - Regional Plan Association/Madison Square Garden, 2013 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
    Includes the RPA's letter to the City Planning Commission opposing Madison Square Garden's request for an infinite special zoning permit to operate its arena above Pennsylvania Station, Zuccotti's email in disagreement with the RPA's position, Paul Selver's testimony on behalf of the Garden, and other documents.